<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>T. B. Árting: Resume on Trygvi Bech Árting</title>
    <link>http://tarting.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in T. B. Árting: Resume on Trygvi Bech Árting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://tarting.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kriging and map projection</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/repository/kriging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/repository/kriging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An example of kriging and map projection in Python 3. Geopandas is used for reading and plotting data from shapefiles; pyproj for projecting data from geographic coortinates to UTM coordinates; the kriging solution from osgeo, gstools is used to fit the data, and generate conditioned fields; shapely is used to generate geometries; scipy.ndimage is used for vector-raster arithmetic; numpy for array manipulations; and matplotlib for ploting maps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Config</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/repository/pysotope/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/repository/pysotope/config/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pysotope package is highly configurable using javascript object notation files for storing isotope system configuration.
These files contain all information about how to read the data files, which filetype plugin to use, spike-standard compostion etc.
Here an example configuration file is presented with comments on each parameter. Comments are not allowed in the regular json files used for data reduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readme</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/repository/pysotope/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/repository/pysotope/readme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pysotope uses a hillclimbing algorithm to unmix spike and sample isotope composition, by calculating mass dependent instrument and natural isotope fractionation from a known standard. This yields sample isotope composition and concentration for the element of interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. B. Árting: Reach Me</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/reachme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/reachme/</guid>
      <description>Reach me at  e-mail: trygvi@gmail.com
telephone: +45 5031 0807
Social media  ResearchGate
GitHub
Facebook</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. B. Árting: Research</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interest  My current research interests derive from my desire to apply novel analytical approaches to understanding ancient Earth processes. Including development of the hydrosphere and atmosphere, as well as understanding orogenic igneous processes. I am currently working on tracing atmospheric oxygen in the Late Neoproterozoic in banded iron formations and carbonates in Brazil and Canada, on the petrology of the noritic Tasiilaq Intrusion, South-East Greenland, and the behaviour of Cr isotopes in the Paleoproterozoic Quadrilátero Ferífero banded iron formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. B. Árting: Resume</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>About me  Halló, I am a geologist from the Faroe Islands, currently based in Copenhagen Denmark. Until recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been employed as a PhD-student at the University of Copenhagen. During my stay I implemented new data reduction schemes for the mass spectrometry lab (TIMS), and established methods for trace metal analysis in geological samples using inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS, Bruker Aurora Elite), and was involved in method development for laser ablation ICP-MS in a newly established laboratory (Teledyne CETAC Analyte Excite coupled with Agilent 7900 ICP-MS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tarting.xyz</title>
      <link>http://tarting.github.io/repository/tarting.xyz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tarting.github.io/repository/tarting.xyz/</guid>
      <description>Source code for this website at github.com/tarting/tarting.xyz. The website was is generated using the hugo static website generator, heavily based on the researcher theme. Gallery functionality is provided by nanogallery2 following mertbakirs guide. Nanogallery2 and single image displays on the site depend on lightbox2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
